A Guide to the James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1976-1990
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
James J. Kilpatrick Papers, 1976-1990
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6626-n
5000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by James J. Kilpatrick on April 25, 1990.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the James J. Kilpatrick papers contains reader mail to Kilpatrick's columns and appearances on "Agronsky and Company." The chief topics are abortion; animal rights; armed services retirement benefits; government subsidizing of the arts; the United States budget; government bureauracy; the U.S. Congress; conservatism; conservation; constitutional interpretation; education; foreign affairs; gun control; the Iran/Contra affair; and lawyers.
Also discussed are nuclear disarmament; the presidential election of 1988; pornography; Ronald Reagan; race relations, affirmative action and reverse discrimination; religion; particularly Supreme Court decisions and the 1st Amendment; Scrabble, Virginia; Social Security; the Supreme Court; and South Africa.
The collection also contains two drafts of The Writer's Art, a manuscript of A Bestiary of Bridge, material on the Democratic convention of 1980, and a file of background material on Robert Bork.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by subject under two series: Reader Mail, and Miscellaneous.
Contents List
- Reader Mail
  - Abortion 1985-1989, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Agriculture 1985 (Box 1)
  - Animals 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Armed Forces 1985, 1987, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Art 1985-1990, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Books 1985-1989, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Budget, United States 1987-1989, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Bureaucracy 1985, 1987-1989, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Catfish 1986 (Box 3)
  - Cigarettes 1985-1989 (Box 3)
  - Combs, Lou 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Communism 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Congress 1986-1989, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Conservatism 1986-1989 (Box 4)
  - Conservatism 1986-1989, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Constitution 1985 (Box 4)
  - Constitution 1986-1990, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Courts 1985-1988, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Courts 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Education 1985-1988, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Environment 1988 (Box 6)
  - ERA 1986 (Box 6)
  - Federalism 1986 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Affairs 1985-1989, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Government 1985 (Box 7)
  - Guns 1985, 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Harris, Jean 1986 (Box 7)
  - Health Care 1987-1989 (Box 8)
  - Homosexuals 1989 (Box 8)
  - Hunting 1989-1990 (Box 8)
  - Iran/Contra 1986-1989, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Judges 1987 (Box 8)
  - Law 1985-1988, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Media 1985-1989 (Box 8)
  - Newspapers 1985-1989, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Nukes 1985-1988, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Politics 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Politics 1987-1990, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Polls 1985 (Box 10)
  - Pornography 1985-1987, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Postal Service 1985, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Press 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Prostitution 1986 (Box 11)
  - Race 1984-1989, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Reagan 1985-1989, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Religion 1985-1987, 7 folders (Box 12)
  - Religion 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Scrabble 1985-1989, 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Social Security 1985-1989, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Supreme Court 1985-1989, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Taxation 1987, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Transportation 1989 (Box 15)
  - United Nations 1986 (Box 15)
  - Welfare 1985 (Box 15)
  - Women Orators 1988 (Box 15)
  - The Writer's Art 1986 (Box 15)
  - Writing 1985-1989 (Box 15)
- Miscellaneous
  - "The Art of the Craft" Red Smith Lecture in Journalism by James J. Kilpatrick 1985 (Box 15)
  - A Bestiary of Bridge by James J. Kilpatrick with Drawings by Lee Lorenz n.d., TMS (Box 15)
  - Bork, Robert: Materials re Supreme Court Nomination 1986-1987, 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Campaign 80 CBS NEWS - "The Democratic National Convention" 1980 Aug 12-13 (Box 16)
  - Campaign 80 CBS NEWS - "Vote Analysis Handbook" 1980 (Box 16)
  - Contracts 1978 (Box 16)
  - Elmlark, Harry E.: Correspondence 1976-1981 (Box 17)
  - "Miranda v. Arizona: Twenty Years After" in Criminal Justice Ethics by James J. Kilpatrick 1986 (Box 17)
  - The Writer's Art, Amended and Corrected Version 1983 Nov 29, TMs; 3 folders (Box 17)
  - The Writer's Art, Final Draft 1984 Feb 29, TMs; 3 folders (Box 17)